And so I'll give you
a couple of examples.
So the point is the
last 20 centuries,
we were really just
getting warmed up
when it comes to this material.
What the recent understanding
of how to engineer this material
has led to are real
breakthrough ideas.
And so I'll show you just a
couple in my why this matters.
Because glass is, after
all, made of-- there
it is up there in
case you can't see it.
This is the abundance of
elements versus atomic number,
and you notice the
very top two elements
are silicon and oxygen. And so
it would be really nice if we
could make a lot of
stuff out of these really
abundant cheap elements.
Think sand.
Could I take sand and make
a lot of stuff out of it?
Well, not if I can't control.
Not if I have to heat it up to
3,000 degrees or its viscosity
isn't what I want or it doesn't
give me the properties I want,
but that has changed.
That has fundamentally changed.
So we can now look at
materials like this,
these super-abundant materials,
and we can completely
rethink them.
And I'll give you one example.
It's already a few
years old, but I
think it's just a
really cool idea, which
is called the Solar Sinter.
And here he's
developed this machine
that is entirely solar powered.
They're solar cells
for the electricity.
And it's a focused beam
of light from the sun that
gets hot enough to
engineer the glass.
So he takes sand from
the desert that he's in.
He puts it in a container,
and he's got a 3D printer
that he's made.
It's entirely solar powered.
There's no fossil fuels, but
he can take sand and turn it
into something structural.
And so there's a
vase that he's made,
and you can take that out.
And again, that's
just the beginning
of rethinking what we could
do with these super-abundant
materials.